Hector Francisco Garcia Lara

Full-Stack Web Software Developer

hectorglara@outlook.com http://hectorglara.ninja +1 809 819 9136

Morris Ave. 2819, NY, EEUU

Dear Mr. / Ms.

I am a passionate Full Stack Web Software Developer with five years of experience in National/International companies along the commercial and financial sector.

I have always thought in doing my best, I don't like my software return to me when it's in Q&A department. I secure my commit will be working and optimized for the application I developed.

I have worked from database construction to the front-end view using different tools what doing my work more interesting:

- 1. SSIS/SSRS (Reporting and Integration Services).
- SQL SERVER.
 C# .NET CORE MVC/WEB API
- 4. ANGULARJS / ANGULAR

In short, I adapt to any software development platforms.

"The hard work in anytime have its reward"

Héctor García

Hector Francisco **Garcia Lara**

Full-Stack Web Software Developer



WORK EXPERIENCE

2015-PRESENT

Software Developer

At Banco de Reservas

■ Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

My principal functions are: Discuss technical solutions with customers and users providing innovate new ideas, Develop applications wih high quality, Create methologies and resources for impplementing software towards excellent way.

I have leaded project such as: Fiscal Ivoincing, Credit Request, Employees Evaluation, Invoice Automatic Generation and Certificates of Deposit.

2014-2015

Software Consultant

At Infosyp

▼ Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

Contribute with the software implementation of different companies' projects, develop and test the best solutions for the project will be more optimum and easy for the users and customers working closely with the Tech Leads and Development Managers.

2012 - 2014

• Flat Software Developer

At Grupo Astro SRL

▼ Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

Create, update and maintain the different software of our company to fulfill customers and user's needs.

I had the opportunity of work in two important projects: **Certification Fiscal**, it was a project that permitted the company verify its point of sale software to can be sold to different companies; **Security Software**, in this project I had to travel for testing the different security control in the place and adapt the software with Gartner devices (http://www.gartner.com/)

2009 - 2012

• Junior Software Developer

At QUALA SA

▼ Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

I was developing financial software for automatize process which are: Conciliation Bank, Customer's Payments, Plane File Generation for Import Data to others Software Platforms and Fulfillment checker (Software for auditing employees). Also I was lead software tester in Financial Department (Project of Centralization and Unification, Updating ERP).

1

WHY MF?

I am a passionate web software developer (FrontEnd/BackEnd) with 5+ years of experience in

National/International companies along the commercial and finance sector.

I adapt to any software development platforms.

⋄ SKILLS

| .NET | • • • • • |
|-------------------|-----------|
| JavaScript | • • • • • |
| SQL SERVER | • • • • • |
| AngularJS/Angular | • • • • • |
| SSIS/SSRS | • • • • • |
| Html/CSS | • • • • • |
| Photoshop | • • • • • |
| NodeJS | • • • • • |
| Web API | • • • • • |
| Oracle | • • • • • |



LANGUAGES

 \times

hectorglara@outlook.com



+1 809 819 9136



https://www.linkedin.com/in/hectorglara

EDUCATION

2014 - 2018 • Bachelor Degree Software Engineering

At Universidad Tecnológica de Santiago Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic Software Development and Architecture

2004 - 2008 • High School Degree Computer/Software

At Instituto Técnico Salesiano

Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

Data Base Administration, Web/Desktop Development, Algorithms, Designs

Patterns.

2000 - 2004 • Primary School

At Oratorio Maria Auxiliadora

▼ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

Awards

2017 • 1st Efficient in problems resolution - CORE BANK

At BanReservas

▼ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

2010 • Individual Recognition - Administration and Finances

At Quala SA

♥ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

2011 ● Best Team

At Quala SA

▼ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

X

Tools I Can Manage

How I said above, I'm able to use many development's platforms, but there are I can really manage day by day:

Frontend Development

As principal tool I use is Angular 4 / AngularJS, It gives me all what I need with others third parts components (DevExpress/PrimeNG/JQuery/Jasmine) to develop any software.

Backend Development

As principal tool I use is Visual Studio ASP.NET MCV/WEB API with SQL SERVER x Version, also SSIS/SSRS (Integration/Reporting Services).

+1 809 819 9136

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/hectorglara